# ANDREW FILLMORE

Chicago, IL | <u>andrew.fillmore@gmail.com</u> | 503-804-5099 | <u>andrewfillmore.com</u> <u>GitHub</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u>

## FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I am a developer, artist and educator experienced in managing projects from concept to production, delivering creative solutions. Throughout my professional experience I understand the importance of self learning and the process of discovery. I enjoy bringing my research, organization, creativity, and problem solving skills to collaborative projects.

## **SKILLS**

**Technical**: Ruby, Rails, Vue.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, APIs, Pair-Programming, Testing, Object-Oriented Programming, Bootstrap

**Design/Production**: Adobe Creative Suite, Phase One, Capture One, large format digital printing (including RIP software), comprehensive knowledge of studio lighting and camera systems

### **EDUCATION**

## **Actualize Coding Bootcamp**

# **Certificate in Full Stack Web Development**

**April 2021 - July 2021** 

- Capstone Project ("One Easy Plate"): personally built a web app that provides users who may be inexperienced in the kitchen easy access and instructions for simple, healthy recipes with few ingredients. This app accesses a third-party api to retrieve recipes and allows users to store favorites for future reference. I created a wireframe, utilized Vue.js to implement a frontend interface, and Ruby on Rails for the backend database and schema.
- **Bootcamp:** Learned fundamentals and best practices in full-stack web development in areas of project architecture, backend, frontend, and how to effectively self-teach new technologies
  - Generated technical requirements and determined the most effective solutions, created wireframes, designed schema, and researched outside resources
  - o Built and tested the backend, incorporating external APIs
  - Created pages and RESTful routes, made web requests to retrieve data, formatted and styled results, incorporated libraries and themes

Rhode Island School of Design | Master of Fine Arts, Photography Lewis and Clark College | Bachelor of Arts, History, Philosophy **June 2012** 

#### EXPERIENCE

# **Luxury Garage Sale**

## **Lead Photographer**

March 2019 - March 2020

- Created imagery for all Marketing and Social Media channels of rotating inventory of high-end fashion apparel and accessories
- Photographed and created a database of unique imagery for national print and digital advertising
- Defined shooting standards for all studio product and editorial photography

# **Adjunct Professor - Photography**

**January 2013 - June 2020** 

Brown University | Rhode Island School of Design | City College New York, CUNY New Jersey City University | Cooper Union School of Art | College of DuPage

- Developed curriculum for Studio Lighting, Digital Photography I and II, Advanced Analog Printing, Alternative Process Photography, Photographic Projects and the Book
- Taught a range of software including Phase One/Capture and Adobe Creative Suite: Photoshop, Lightroom, InDesign, Illustrator, Premiere Pro. Self taught software for use in classroom instruction.
- Taught Profoto and Broncolor strobe and light shaping equipment for product and portraiture lighting
- Established best practices for students to carry into professional studio scenarios

### **Crate and Barrel**

# **Photographer - Contract**

March 2017 - March 2019

- Collaborated with art directors and stylists photographing new seasonal product lines in accordance with style guides for e-commerce marketing
- Worked with Capture One and Adobe software to streamline photographic output for use in digital and print publication
- Produced up to 20 unique final product images per day with retouching edits

### **GE** Healthcare

## **Photographer - Contract**

December 2019 - March 2020

- Produced 360 degree photography using proprietary software of for a range of GE Healthcare products
- Photographed over 1500 products for redesign of GE Healthcare B2B site
- Built a custom on-site photo studio at GE Healthcare Distribution facility for secure transfer of products

### Freelance Production Artist / Retoucher

2014 - 2017

Select clients include: AT&T, National Football League, Major League Baseball, Verizon, JP Morgan, Johnson & Johnson, New York Historical Society

- Retouched photography for interactive, print, and web solutions for a range of clients
- Designed brochures and layouts for print, catalog and interactive products